I'm going to tell you about Bubble Finesse.
I think Bubble Finesse is a really cute word.
And it actually is a technical wine tasting term use for the quality of the bubble display and texture in a sparkling wine.
If a sparkling wine has excellent bubble finesse, it has lots and lots of bubbles.
The more, the better.
It also has very small bubbles.
The smaller, the better.
Also the bubbles will form this beautiful straight little trains, or streams.
They won't bounce all over the place, they just rise from bottom of the glass or wherever the bubble start and they go straight up to the top.
This is actually called the point of bubble nucleation, at the bottom of the glass.
And I call that straight streams, bouncing, behaving bubbles or bubbles at behave.
Also when you taste a glass of sparkling wine, the bubbles should be so many and so small, lets try it, that they form like a creamy texture.
In other words, that even though this wine is very tart and very acidic and refreshing, it should be smooth and soft because the bubbles kind of melt into one another and make like a cashmere blanket over your tongue.
So the more bubbles, the smaller the bubbles.
Bubbles that form trains.
Bubbles that behave.
Bubbles that start at the bottom, come to the top and explode.
Bubbles that form a nice, smooth, cashmere kind of blanket over your tongue.
These are all good things in sparkling wine and they're called Bubble Finesse.